# Derek Misler web & Software Developer

## **About Derek**

I am a full-stack web and software developer with 10+ years experience. I have a well-rounded education, both traditional and self-driven, of many different web and software programming languages for both desktop and mobile, including Python, Ruby, C/C++, C#/.NET, PHP, and an advanced proficiency of front-end techniques involving HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, including frameworks such as jQuery, Angular, and React. Some of my favorite aspects of web development and software engineering are solving complex data-related problems, optimization and analysis of data sets such as A/B testing, and finding bugs through a test-driven development approach. I am an independent person, but I enjoy the learning opportunities afforded by working on a team.

For more information and a portfolio of work, including links to Github repositories, StackOverflow and LinkedIn profiles, visit <u>DerekMisler.com</u>.

## Career

# Asheville Area Chamber of Commerce, Convention & Visitors Bureau

2011-2016

#### Web Manager

As the only designer/developer/analyst on staff, my job is to maintain our entire web presence. I've been on board for two redesigns, first a .NET-backed site, and more recently with a responsive site developed primarily in Node.js on the back-end, and a custom JS framework, Goatee, on the front-end.

Houser Shoes 2010-2011

## Web Designer/Photographer

During my time at Houser Shoes, I was part of a 3 person team that redesigned their e-commerce website. We created a custom CMS based on Magento, which utilized primarily PHP and MySQL.

## Freelance Designer/Developer

2009-2016

Mostly branding and corporate identity at first, but I eventually had enough clients needing new websites that I became a full-time developer.

## **Precision Printing**

2007-2009

## **Designer/Printer**

Though this isn't programming- or web-related, I still think my experience working in a print shop can be seen in my work as a developer. Printing requires an extremely detail-oriented approach as there is no room for error.

## The Appalachian Newspaper

2006-2008

## Lead Designer/Developer

I worked with an intern to establish an online presence for The Appalachian newspaper, while still maintaining my role as the lead graphic designer.

## **Education**

# **Appalachian State University**

2005-2009

#### **BFA - Graphic Design**

The curriculum path I chose focused on web development while also teaching color theory, typography, and layout design in a group setting. I think all developers should have an eye for design, and I believe having this well-rounded education makes me a unique candidate for a position at any company.

# A.C. Reynolds High School

2000-2004

Why would I add high school to this list? Because this is when I started my development career, over 15 years ago. I built my first website with PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in 2000 and started with C++ shortly thereafter. It was here that I learned the conventions behind object-oriented programming.

# **Independent Learning**

Harvard

**CS50x3: Computer Science** 

Codecademy

AngularJS

Codecademy/Code School JavaScript

Code School

Shaping Up with Angular.js

code School jQuery

Udemy

**Ruby Programming for Beginners** 

Udemy

Beginner Python & Django Programming

Microsof

DEV204: Programming with C#

Codecademy

**JavaScript APIs** 

Code School **Ruby** 

Code School

Git

Free Code Camp

**Full Stack Web Development** 

Udemy

Advanced Ruby: 10 Steps to Mastery

Udemv

Python, The Next Level

## **Proficiencies**

Adobe CS	****
HTML5/CSS3	****
CSS Preprocessors	****
Actionscript	****
PHP	****
C#	****
Ruby	****
NFT	****

Git/Github

JavaScript/jQuery

Angular/React

Node.js

Python

C/C++

ColdFusion

Java